<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ad on Hugo's IT journal</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/ad/</link><description>Recent content in ad on Hugo's IT journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/ad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure Identity Management</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-identity-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-identity-management/</guid><description>Identity Protection # Conditional Access # Purpose to enforce specific controls on access to apps based on certain conditions.
For example, MFA enforcement can be found under the Grant control section.</description></item><item><title>Azure AD</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-ad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-ad/</guid><description>Users # If a user is synced from an external source, JobTitle cannot be modified. But UsageLocation can be updated.
Bulk Operations # Create a CSV file contains the necessary fields</description></item><item><title>Setting up ADFS Login in AWS with Windows Server 2012</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-adfs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-adfs/</guid><description>Create a new Windows Server 2012 instance and install the following Roles and Features:
DNS ADFS AD Promote the server to a Domain Controller and create a new forest. I named mine hhuge9.</description></item><item><title>Active Directory Issues and Solutions</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/windows-ad-issues/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/windows-ad-issues/</guid><description>DC Cannot Replicate # Problem: Target principal name incorrect during AD replication Solution (Demote and Promote AD): Demote the DC at &amp;ldquo;Remove Roles and Features&amp;rdquo; Manually clean update the metadata: Remove the DC record at AD Users and Computers Remove the DC-related record at AD Sites and Services &amp;amp; in DNS Promote the DC back Result: Replication resumes, syncing with other DCs For &amp;ldquo;PRC server not operating&amp;rdquo; error, check DNS issues with dcdiag and try dns scavenging PDC Gone, Operation Master Role not Transferred # Solution: Forceful Takeover Use Move-ADDirectoryServerOperationMasterRole to move the Operation Master.</description></item></channel></rss>