<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azure on Hugo's IT journal</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in azure on Hugo's IT journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure Cosmos</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-cosmos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-cosmos/</guid><description>Cosmos DB is the only DB service supports multi-master writes across multiple regions
This feature allows for write operations in any region, providing low-latency writes globally
Cosmos DB supports multiple APIs, including</description></item><item><title>Azure Data</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-data/</guid><description>Batch # Azure Batch offers two pool allocation modes:
Batch service User subscription Batch service: (prefered)
Pools are allocated in Batch-managed subscriptions Supports dedicated VMs and Azure Spot VMs User subscription:</description></item><item><title>Azure Migration</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-migration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-migration/</guid><description>Azure Migrate # Azure Migrate can be using for planning and executing VMware migrations to Azure
Can give migration plan for VMWare Migration Discover and assess on-premises VMware VMs Provide sizing and cost estimation for Azure VMs Using Azure Site Recovery under the hood for the actual replication and migration process SQL Server Migration # Azure Database Migration Service (via Azure Data Studio) is best for large-scale migrations with minimal administrative effort Data Migration Assistant is a good second choice for more controlled, smaller migrations SQL Server Migration Assistant is specifically for migrating from non-SQL Server databases Azure Database Migration Service (DMS) # Integrated into Azure Data Studio via the Azure SQL Migration extension Supports migrating SQL Server databases to: Azure SQL Managed Instance SQL Server on Azure VM Azure SQL Database (offline mode only) Offers online (minimal downtime) and offline migration modes Provides assessment, SKU recommendations, and orchestrates the migration process Data Migration Assistant (DMA) # Standalone tool for assessing and migrating SQL Server databases Good for smaller migrations Can migrate to Azure SQL Database, Azure SQL Managed Instance, and SQL Server on Azure VM Provides compatibility assessment before migration SQL Server Migration Assistant (SSMA) # Used for migrating non-SQL Server databases (e.</description></item><item><title>Azure SQL Server</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-sql/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-sql/</guid><description>Data Encryption (PII) = Always Encrypted
Key Considerations # For HA: Business Critical or Hyperscale For cost-effective HA solution: General Purpose For multiple databases with varying workloads: Elastic Pool For SQL Server features not available in Azure SQL Database: Managed Instance Azure Synapse Analytics is optimized for data warehousing and analytics workloads, not for OLTP scenarios Azure Hybrid Benefit for SQL Server can only be applied to the vCore-based purchasing model Zone Redundancy # Supported</description></item><item><title>Azure Application Proxy</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app-proxy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app-proxy/</guid><description>Entra Connect # It is a service that integrates on-premises AD with Azure AD.
Entra Connect Health can be configured to send notifications if there are any AD sync issues.</description></item><item><title>Azure Enterprise Application</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app/</guid><description>Enterprise Application # Enterprise Applications in Entra ID serve as a bridge between various resources and identities.
On-premise app to Azure resource: Uses service principal On-premise resource to Azure resource: Uses service principal User to Azure resource: Uses user or group Azure resource to Azure resource: Uses managed identity Configure Enterprise Application # Create the app in Entra ID Grant permissions to the service principal (the app) Create a client ID and secret Use these credentials in the app to access Azure resources SSO Options # SAML-based # For applications that support SAML, like AWS Console:</description></item><item><title>Azure Flexible Server (MySQL)</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-db/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-db/</guid><description>HA is not supported in the Burstable compute tier HA is available for General Purpose and Business Critical tiers HA Options:
Zone-redundant HA: Provides redundancy across AZs. Same-zone HA: Provides redundancy within AZ.</description></item><item><title>Azure Flexible Server (MySQL)</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-mysql/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-mysql/</guid><description>HA is not supported in the Burstable compute tier HA is available for General Purpose and Business Critical tiers HA Options:
Zone-redundant HA: Provides redundancy across AZs. Same-zone HA: Provides redundancy within AZ.</description></item><item><title>Azure Identity Management</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-identity-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-identity-management/</guid><description>Identity Protection # Conditional Access # Purpose to enforce specific controls on access to apps based on certain conditions.
For example, MFA enforcement can be found under the Grant control section.</description></item><item><title>Azure AD</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-ad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-ad/</guid><description>Users # If a user is synced from an external source, JobTitle cannot be modified. But UsageLocation can be updated.
Bulk Operations # Create a CSV file contains the necessary fields</description></item><item><title>Azure Functions</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-function/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-function/</guid><description> Tiers # Consumption Plan # Event-driven and automatically scales Limited to 10 minutes execution time by default (can be extended to 60 minutes with configuration) Cold starts Pay only for the time your code runs Does not support VNet integration Premium Plan # No cold starts (always warm) Unlimited execution time Pay for pre-warmed instances Supports VNet integration Dedicated (App Service) Plan # Runs on App Service VMs Can run continuously Supports VNet integration</description></item><item><title>Azure Key Vault</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-key-vault/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-key-vault/</guid><description>Access control # Azure Key Vault offers two main methods for controlling access:
Access Policies (legacy) Role-Based Access Control (RBAC) - recommended Access Policies # Applied at the Key Vault level Permissions granted affect all keys within the vault Less granular control compared to RBAC RBAC # Can be set at either the Key Vault or Object level Allows for more granular permissions (e.</description></item><item><title>Azure Monitoring</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-monitoring/</guid><description>Monitor Tools # Azure Activity Log is equivalent to AWS CloudTrail. Azure Advisor: Provides recommendations for cost savings and best practices. Traffic Analytics: showing statistics, summary, numbers of the network Application Insight # It is a powerful application performance management tool.</description></item><item><title>Azure Storage Account</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-storage-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-storage-account/</guid><description>Evolution # StorageV1: Original BlobStorage: Introduced for Blob-specific capabilities StorageV2: Added ZRS support Data Lake Gen2: Supports Hierarchical Namespace, POSIX ACL, HDFS protocol Limitations # StorageV1: No Blob features, no ZRS support ZRS: Not in StorageV1.</description></item><item><title>Azure App Service</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app-service/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-app-service/</guid><description>The region of the App and App Service Plan should be matched.
App Service Plan defines the underlying infrastructure and resources for hosting applications.
This includes the OS (Windows/Linux), Region, no of instances, instance type, and pricing tier.</description></item><item><title>Azure Container Services</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-container-services/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-container-services/</guid><description>AKS # Azure AD Authentication # Legacy Method:
Create an app in EntraID manually Assign directory read role to the app Link the app with AKS az aks update-credentials \ --resource-group myResourceGroup \ --name myAKSCluster \ --reset-aad \ --aad-client-app-id &amp;lt;client-id&amp;gt; \ --aad-server-app-id &amp;lt;server-id&amp;gt; \ --aad-server-app-secret &amp;lt;server-secret&amp;gt; \ --aad-tenant-id &amp;lt;tenant-id&amp;gt; Current Method:</description></item><item><title>Azure Logic App</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-logic-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-logic-app/</guid><description>Logic Apps is a cloud service that allows us to automate workflows, business processes.
It&amp;rsquo;s similar to Power Automate / IFFF but offers more advanced capabilities and is designed for more complex scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Azure VM</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-vm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-vm/</guid><description>Instance Types # D series: General Purpose; S for SSD M / E series: Memory optimized F series: Compute optimized H series: HPC L series: Disk optimized N series: GPU (NVIDIA) DNS Formats # internal: &amp;lt;vm-name&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title>Azure ARM Template</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-arm-template/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-arm-template/</guid><description>We can view resources deployed via ARM templates at:
Resource Group &amp;gt; Deployments When using count, the copyIndex() function starts counting from 0.
&amp;#34;resources&amp;#34;: [ { &amp;#34;type&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;Microsoft.Storage/storageAccounts&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;name&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[concat(&amp;#39;storage&amp;#39;, copyIndex())]&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;apiVersion&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;2022-01-01&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;location&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;[resourceGroup().</description></item><item><title>Azure Backup</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-backup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-backup/</guid><description>Recovery Service Vault # The Vault needs to be in the same region as the VM.
The vault includes two primary services:
Backup Service Recovery Service (for Disaster Recovery) Backup:</description></item><item><title>Azure Resource Group</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-resource-group/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-resource-group/</guid><description>Resource Mover # We can move a resource between resource groups within the same subscription or to a different subscription.
The resource&amp;rsquo;s location will stay the same during the move.</description></item><item><title>Azure Networking</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-network/</guid><description>Network Interface # A single NIC can have multiple public and private IPs. Network Security Group (NSG) # NSG is stateful and contains inbound and outbound rules.
Service Tags are named groups that refer to Azure services (e.</description></item><item><title>Azure ACL</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-acl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-acl/</guid><description>IAM Roles # Access rights to Azure resources:
Owner: Full access, including assigning roles and policies. User Access Administrator: Assign roles/policies. Contributor: Create and manage (read and write) resources. Reader: View resources (read-only).</description></item><item><title>Azure Disk</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-disk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-disk/</guid><description>Disk Type # SSD # Standard SSD: General Purpose Premium SSD: Support high IOPS Ultra Disk: High-performance option (Overskill for most scenarios) HDD # Standard HDD Disk Caching # Azure provides three caching options for disks:</description></item><item><title>Azure Powershell</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-cmd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-cmd/</guid><description>Naming Conventions # Prefix:
Azure: Older prefix for Azure PowerShell cmdlets. Rm: Resource Manager (older prefix). Az: Newer prefix for Azure PowerShell cmdlets. Actions:
Get-: Returns an object. e.g. Get-AzVM Retrieves details of a virtual machine.</description></item><item><title>Azure Storage Tools</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-storage-tools/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/azure-storage-tools/</guid><description>Summary # Service File Storage Blob Storage AzCopy Yes Yes Import/Export Yes Yes File Sync Yes No Auth\Tool AD Account Key SAS SMB Yes Yes No AzCopy Yes Yes Yes CLI Yes Yes Yes File Sync # Similar to Google Drive, File Sync allows us to synchronize folders on Windows with a file share.</description></item><item><title>Coretek's cloud migration methodology</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tj3F0tX8eyc
6:26 - 5 steps
Assess # Cloud Economic Assessment (8:20) # understand resources needed on-premise (mem, storage, bandwidth)
Plan # use cloud adoption framework (10:45) Migrate # Cloud Migration Strategies (4:30) # Rehost - create vm on cloud and move application to it</description></item><item><title>EKS vs AKS</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/eks-vs-aks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/eks-vs-aks/</guid><description>Control Panel Fee # AKS: 0 EKS: fixed charge 0.1 USD / Hour Integration # I think AKS is better, most of the provisioning plugins can be enabled by one click</description></item></channel></rss>