<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Hugo's IT journal</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Hugo's IT journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ALB and API Gateway</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-alb-and-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-alb-and-api-gateway/</guid><description>ALB> ALB # Two connections maintained: ALB to target servers. Client to ALB. Keepalive/h2 setting: Applies to ALB-to-target connection, not client-to-target servers. Sticky session: Cookie-based. Why Keepalive help to improve the performance: Limited number of connections between ALB to target servers, keepalive helps.</description></item><item><title>S3</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-s3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-s3/</guid><description>Public Access Object Setup with ACL &amp;amp; Bucket Policy:> Public Access Object Setup with ACL &amp;amp; Bucket Policy: # Using ACL:> Using ACL: # Disable block public access ACL. Select objects and make them public.</description></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-aurora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-aurora/</guid><description>RDS Read Replica> RDS Read Replica # cross AZ: OK cross region: OK promote / point-in-time recovery / restore from snapshot will create a new db instance which is not in my expectation.</description></item><item><title>Opsworks</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-opsworks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-opsworks/</guid><description>OpsWorks> OpsWorks # stack = cookbooks layer = frontend, backend, api, rds (how to config to instance) app = source code. can deploy and redeploy Stack> Stack # I am exploring this cookbook from aws The nodejs demo cookbook repo does not include its dependencies In the opsworks demo, it uses opsworks-linux-demo-cookbooks-nodejs.</description></item><item><title>Coretek's cloud migration methodology</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tj3F0tX8eyc
6:26 - 5 steps
Assess> Assess # Cloud Economic Assessment (8:20)> Cloud Economic Assessment (8:20) # understand resources needed on-premise (mem, storage, bandwidth)
Plan> Plan # use cloud adoption framework (10:45) Migrate> Migrate # Cloud Migration Strategies (4:30)> Cloud Migration Strategies (4:30) # Rehost - create vm on cloud and move application to it</description></item><item><title>A Roadmap to Cloud Centre of Excellence Adoption</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/cloud-center-of-excellenace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/cloud-center-of-excellenace/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mUTGdSA60Ao
introduction - Cloud Centre of Excellence is a team that can help the organisation for cloud adoption role &amp;amp; responsible characteristic for the team member best practice Characteristic> Characteristic # driving the organisation forward has ability to stand up - open-minded be confident why and how to do it - clear minded / big picture thinkers diverse and cross-functional Skill Set> Skill Set # Cost management Project Management (Transparent) Cloud operation engineer (CI/CD) Data engineer (new currency, capture data from IoT, video stream) Application Security (IAM, Policy, Firewall) Best Practise> Best Practise # Keep passion &amp;amp; excitement Start small (5-7 ppl in a team) Rotate people (training) Communication Scaling and reorganising Think of the failover and backup plan Cloud training for organisation Bill, cost optimization Empower the team (courage them trying new role, new service, bleeding-edge tech) Gain transparency (everyone knows the progress&amp;hellip;why you do that&amp;hellip;) Notes> Notes # cloud makes anything as code -&amp;gt; code makes things more transparent -&amp;gt; the complexity of the project is reduced many jobs can be automated through cloud and they are automatically documented as code is it possible to create a roadmap / resources library for the whole organisation (like AWS workshop)?</description></item></channel></rss>