<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud on Hugo's IT journal</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in cloud on Hugo's IT journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Secure API Gateway with Cognito</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-with-cognito/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-with-cognito/</guid><description>To enable authorization the api with Amazon Cognito User Pools:
Create a user pool. Check out Secure your API Gateway with Amazon Cognito User Pools for a video tutorial. In the &amp;ldquo;Method Request&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Auth&amp;rdquo; section of the API Gateway console, select the user pool.</description></item><item><title>Comparing HTTP and REST API Gateways</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-comparson/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-comparson/</guid><description>Main difference> Main difference # REST HTTP Quota Management Per group Not supported API key Management Supported Not supported Authorization Lambda/Cognito Lambda/IAM/JWT Lambda Input Payload only Request details (Event) VTL model Supported Not supported SDK and Documentation Generation Supported Not supported Lambda integration> Lambda integration # Both REST and HTTP Lambda integrations offer a powerful and flexible way to integrate Lambda functions with API Gateway, with some differences in input/output format and response handling.</description></item><item><title>Creating a Signed AWS API Request: A Handy Guide</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-sign-v4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-sign-v4/</guid><description>To create a signed AWS API request, follow the detailed guide provided in Create a signed AWS API request.
To generate a signed request in Python, you can use the following script created by ChatGPT:</description></item><item><title>Understanding OAuth 2.0: An Overview with Amazon Cognito Implementation</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-cognito/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-cognito/</guid><description>Difference between OAuth2.0, OIDC and SAML2> Difference between OAuth2.0, OIDC and SAML2 # OAuth 2.0 provides authorization using ID token. OIDC provides authentication using access token. SAML2 provides both authentication and authorization.</description></item><item><title>How to host a static website on S3</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-s3-hosting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-s3-hosting/</guid><description>Concepts> Concepts # Block Public Access> Block Public Access # Prevent any public access in ACL or bucket policy. ACL: If you block public access in ACL, any public access granted to everyone will be ignored.</description></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-aurora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-aurora/</guid><description>RDS Read Replica> RDS Read Replica # cross AZ: OK cross region: OK promote / point-in-time recovery / restore from snapshot will create a new db instance which is not in my expectation.</description></item><item><title>Opsworks</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-opsworks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-opsworks/</guid><description>OpsWorks> OpsWorks # stack = cookbooks layer = frontend, backend, api, rds (how to config to instance) app = source code. can deploy and redeploy Stack> Stack # I am exploring this cookbook from aws The nodejs demo cookbook repo does not include its dependencies In the opsworks demo, it uses opsworks-linux-demo-cookbooks-nodejs.</description></item><item><title>Coretek's cloud migration methodology</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/az-migration-strategies/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tj3F0tX8eyc
6:26 - 5 steps
Assess> Assess # Cloud Economic Assessment (8:20)> Cloud Economic Assessment (8:20) # understand resources needed on-premise (mem, storage, bandwidth)
Plan> Plan # use cloud adoption framework (10:45) Migrate> Migrate # Cloud Migration Strategies (4:30)> Cloud Migration Strategies (4:30) # Rehost - create vm on cloud and move application to it</description></item><item><title>A Roadmap to Cloud Centre of Excellence Adoption</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/cloud-center-of-excellenace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/cloud-center-of-excellenace/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mUTGdSA60Ao
introduction - Cloud Centre of Excellence is a team that can help the organisation for cloud adoption role &amp;amp; responsible characteristic for the team member best practice Characteristic> Characteristic # driving the organisation forward has ability to stand up - open-minded be confident why and how to do it - clear minded / big picture thinkers diverse and cross-functional Skill Set> Skill Set # Cost management Project Management (Transparent) Cloud operation engineer (CI/CD) Data engineer (new currency, capture data from IoT, video stream) Application Security (IAM, Policy, Firewall) Best Practise> Best Practise # Keep passion &amp;amp; excitement Start small (5-7 ppl in a team) Rotate people (training) Communication Scaling and reorganising Think of the failover and backup plan Cloud training for organisation Bill, cost optimization Empower the team (courage them trying new role, new service, bleeding-edge tech) Gain transparency (everyone knows the progress&amp;hellip;why you do that&amp;hellip;) Notes> Notes # cloud makes anything as code -&amp;gt; code makes things more transparent -&amp;gt; the complexity of the project is reduced many jobs can be automated through cloud and they are automatically documented as code is it possible to create a roadmap / resources library for the whole organisation (like AWS workshop)?</description></item></channel></rss>