<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>api-gateway on Hugo's IT journal</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/api-gateway/</link><description>Recent content in api-gateway on Hugo's IT journal</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugotkk.github.com/tags/api-gateway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Chat Room with Lambda and Websocket in AWS API Gateway</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-wss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-wss/</guid><description>WebSocket Overview> WebSocket Overview # WebSocket Characteristics Bi-directional, persistent TCP connection between client and server Scaling Limitations WebSocket is stateful, cannot horizontally scale without a backend to store state (eg: Redis) API Gateway with Websocket> API Gateway with Websocket # Benefits</description></item><item><title>Building a Secure API Gateway with Cognito</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-with-cognito/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-with-cognito/</guid><description>To enable authorization the api with Amazon Cognito User Pools:
Create a user pool. Check out Secure your API Gateway with Amazon Cognito User Pools for a video tutorial. In the &amp;ldquo;Method Request&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Auth&amp;rdquo; section of the API Gateway console, select the user pool.</description></item><item><title>Comparing HTTP and REST API Gateways</title><link>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-comparson/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugotkk.github.com/posts/aws-api-gateway-comparson/</guid><description>Main difference> Main difference # REST HTTP Quota Management Per group Not supported API key Management Supported Not supported Authorization Lambda/Cognito Lambda/IAM/JWT Lambda Input Payload only Request details (Event) VTL model Supported Not supported SDK and Documentation Generation Supported Not supported Lambda integration> Lambda integration # Both REST and HTTP Lambda integrations offer a powerful and flexible way to integrate Lambda functions with API Gateway, with some differences in input/output format and response handling.</description></item></channel></rss>